<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[sometimeworld-vault]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/</link><image><url>https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>sometimeworld-vault</title><link>https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 19:38:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 19:38:14 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[st]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>st</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Tanner.md" href="wiki/characters/tanner.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Tanner</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
Oscars first friend after the battle. He dies shortly after.
<br>Infobox

-<br>
-






<br>

<br><br>Tanner was born in the same town as <a class="internal-link" data-href="~~Oscar~~.md" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/characters/~~oscar~~.html" target="_self" rel="noopener"><del></del></a>Oscar<br><br><br><br><br>
<br>From same town as <a class="internal-link" data-href="~~Oscar~~.md" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/characters/~~oscar~~.html" target="_self" rel="noopener"><del></del></a>Oscar.
]]></description><link>https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/characters/tanner.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Characters/Tanner.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[st]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 19:34:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="~~First Contact~~.md" href="wiki/stories/~~first-contact~~.html" target="_self" rel="noopener"><del>First Contact</del></a> [<span class="dataview dataview-inline-query"><span>1005</span></span>]]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Deprecated in suspension<br><br>
This is partially inspired by the opening of Vagabond. A possibly entry point for a journey or ground zero explanation.
<br><br><br>Oscar, an adolescent boy probably too young to fight, wakes up laying on the battlefield. Likely was knocked out and thought dead by both friend and foe very early on in the bout. The battle was over … seemingly, both sides were quiet. Whoever won the fight had likely moved on from the area leaving most of the dead behind, on the ground. Weird, most people would collect their dead and burn or bury them later. Oscar spots a fellow soldier close to his age, introduced as <a class="internal-link" data-href="Tanner.md" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/characters/tanner.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Tanner</a>.<br>After greeting, the other boy points out Oscars injury. Oscar is confused because he doesn't seem to feel too much pain. It seems that his right arm is completely severed at the elbow and the open wound filled with this blue gunk, stopping the bleeding. He should definitely get that checked out ... but he does not feel any pain and seem to be in no danger of dying after all. The other boy suggests to scavenge the armour and weapons of the dead to sell or use in future battles. He notices that many of the dead laying in the mud have the same blue wounds as his. <br>After looking around, Oscar finds some weird looking gadgets he stuffs into his bag as well as a short sword he can wield with his non-dominant hand. As they traverse the battlefield, they test their new weapons by hacking on corpses and finishing off the mortally wounded. He follows Tanner for a bit, and comes across an healthy <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Invader</a>. <br>Tanner jumps in front of Oscar, considering Oscar has only one arm, and is cut down with relative ease thanks to the invader's white-hot <a class="internal-link" data-href="Toa.md" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/proficiency/toa.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Edge</a>.<br>Oscar steps back, in fear and awe at the invader and his wicked blade of light. He suddenly remembers the moments before he was knocked unconscious. He remembered being approached by this very invader and the beginning of the battle and being cut down before he could even process what was happening.<br>He drops his steel sword and raises his hands, understanding he is no match for his opponents sword of light. The invader retracts her blade of light back into her handle and stands by, analyzing Oscar's missing arm and recalling the preceding events. Seemingly impressed (by his affinity to the fungal interface), she approaches Oscar, picks up his sword and places it in Oscars hand. "She wants to fight me again". <br>Should Oscar lose his arm in the 1-1 bout with the invader, instead of the initial battle?<br>After a short exchange, Oscar is overpowered by the invader and held at edge-point on the ground. She goes for a final blow, which Oscar parries to the side with his steel sword. Before the invader is able to make her second attempt, she is interrupted by <a class="internal-link" data-href="Aition.md" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/characters/aition.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aition</a> who had noticed the exchange from the tree line and decided to intervene. They have a brief exchange where Aition ultimately slices her across the abdomen. <br>Oscar stands up and rips the retracted Edge from the invader's cold hands. Still rattled at the loss of his new friend and in awe of these light swords that he now possess, he follows <a class="internal-link" data-href="Aition.md" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/characters/aition.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aition</a> as they continue across the battlefield.<br>Oscar, puzzled at how these devices work, begins to ask about Aition and how he had learned how to use one and about the mysterious blue gunk.<br>Aition reacted standoffish to Oscar, still recently upset by the loss of <a class="internal-link" data-href="{young child}" href="https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/{young child}" target="_self" rel="noopener">{young child}</a> and determined to reach the front line of the invasion. He tells Oscar he has no use for this device due to his missing arm and to return home and trade the device for ...<br>A loud bang is heard in the distance... likely gunpowder. Oscar is left behind in the middle of the forest as Aition continues forward towards it.<br><br><br><br><br>
<br>turning out similar to the incredibles.
]]></description><link>https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/stories/~~first-contact~~.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Stories/~~First Contact~~.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[st]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 19:34:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="The Invasion" href="wiki/stories/the-invasion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Invasion</a> [<span class="dataview dataview-inline-query"><span>991</span></span>]]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
<br>northern coast of archania is convenient cause there is lower population and  density
]]></description><link>https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/wiki/stories/the-invasion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Stories/The Invasion.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[st]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 19:35:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sometimeworld]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
The notes and lore for a world where fungal bio-technology meets medieval society.
<br><br>At year 1005<br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>https://tanger71.github.io/sometimeworld-wiki/index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">index.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[st]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 19:37:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Aition.md" href="wiki/characters/aition.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aition</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Aition, born in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Montmark.md" href="wiki/locations/montmark.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Montmark</a>, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Storguard.md" href="wiki/locations/storguard.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Storguard</a> but knowledgeable in <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Numentellian</a> culture, seeks to find his place in the world that has left him behind.
<br>Infobox

<img alt="aition-idle" src="lib/media/aition-idle.gif"><br>
Seeks to find his place in the world that has left him behind






<br>

<br><br><br><br>Aition grew up in a relatively small fishing town. He worked as a hand in the cargo convoys to and from <a class="internal-link" data-href="Montmark.md" href="wiki/locations/montmark.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Montmark</a>, a nearby city controlled by a lord. Doing so, he picked up lots of gossip and political knowledge of the many nations of Archaina.<br>meh

<br>As he got older, he was recruited into a militia
<br>learned to use the sword and fight. was quite good at it. 
<br>Growing up, Aition was good at most things ... but he was always the second best.

<br>Low ego ... low confidence despite talent
<br>childhood rival high ego ... will do anything for the leg up



<br><br>What is Aitions motivation for the driving plot?

<br>Saving family member?
<br>Killing Maqsud?
<br>Just getting out of a tight spot, but getting cornered at every angle? 

<br>out of the frying pan, into the fire ... constantly


<br>

<br><br><br>temp
When growing up in <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archaina</a>, Aition was not fond of living amongst others. He found most people petty and superficial, bickering over insecurities and spreading rumours. He wants no part of this and spends the majority of his day avoiding stepping on the toes of others. This often leads him to pick the most frictionless course of action if it means less hassle and energy being spent over meaningless quarrels. In this way, Aition is often perceived as self centred due to his lack of interest in others... because he is. But not in a dubious way where he will gloat or step on others to get ahead. He knows his place in the world, but just doesn't have much concern or respect for those around him. He is closed off from others, shrouded behind a protective veil.<br>
This attitude begins to shift as he spends time on <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">the island</a>, and grows an appreciation for cooperation and community. This development culminates with the adoption of <a class="internal-link" data-href="{young child}.md" href="{young child}" target="_self" rel="noopener">{young child}</a> as he finally decides to open his life up to others and discovers the value of service and family.
<br><br><br><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="wiki/Stories/~~First Contact~~.md" data-href="wiki/Stories/~~First Contact~~.md" href="wiki/stories/~~first-contact~~.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">~~First Contact~~</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="wiki/Stories/New Order.md" data-href="wiki/Stories/New Order.md" href="wiki/stories/new-order.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">New Order</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="wiki/Stories/Sometimeworld.md" data-href="wiki/Stories/Sometimeworld.md" href="wiki/stories/sometimeworld.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Sometimeworld</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="wiki/Stories/Time Was.md" data-href="wiki/Stories/Time Was.md" href="wiki/stories/time-was.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Time Was</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="wiki/Stories/The One King.md" data-href="wiki/Stories/The One King.md" href="wiki/stories/the-one-king.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The One King</a><br><br><br><br><img alt="worrier-idle.gif" src="lib/media/worrier-idle.gif" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br>
<img alt="aition-idle.gif" src="lib/media/aition-idle.gif" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br>
<img alt="player-0004.gif" src="lib/media/player-0004.gif" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br><br><br>
<br>
while the world around him is resisting the new fungal order, Aition chooses to assimilate with the newcomers and find his new place in the world. 

<br>
Aition begins as a traveler/pirate/sailor who finds Numentellus. He gets to know the culture and society briefly.

<br>
he learns from a young orphaned boy who he meets soon after his village is razed

<br>the boy learns much about life from Aition… lessons that span cultures and societies. abstract and not bound to upbringing. 
<br>Aition learns much from the boy, of the Shuchu and the islanders’ way of life
<br>Since the boy has no family and is ambitious, he follows Aition to the mainland
<br>just after the invasion, the boy passes away from the acts of the mainlander's xenophobic actions, his own people.
<br>Aition is torn between what side is right or wrong... he travels the land in search for his place in the world. 
<br>this is where his story starts


<br>
a mainlander who wears the clothes of an invader

<br>
he comes across Oscar in his journeys and reminds him of the young islander boy. Out of avoidance and pain, he neglects Oscar leading Oscar to seek mentorship and father-ship elsewhere.

<br>
traits: quiet, 

<br>
After returning to <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mainland</a> from <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Numentellus</a>, Aition is estranged by how different it is.

<br>
He has expected to be welcomes with open arms with the new discoveries and technology he brought back. But most seemed disinterested with his Edge and his fungal technology. Overshadowed by the explosive new discovery, gunpowder.

<br>New King, new politics, new weapons, new religion, and an Aition, who was left behind with the old times and a few Numentellion party tricks.


<br>
Serfdom

]]></description><link>wiki/characters/aition.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Characters/Aition.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:48:30 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/aition-idle.gif" length="0" type="image/gif"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/aition-idle.gif"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Maqsud" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Religious leader and lead founder of the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a>.
<br>Infobox

-<br>
Aspires to be the One King






<br>

<br><br><br>Founder of the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> religion and the father of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu Technology</a>. He has a weird fantasy obsession with the many cultures of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archaina</a> to the extent of changing his name and even the name of his homeland.<br><br><br><br>Originating from the hyperbolized and flowery stories of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Aition.md" href="wiki/characters/aition.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aition</a>'s homeland, Maqsud grew an obsession with the many cultures of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archaina</a>. Although Aition told his stories from his own perspective as a young serf under a feudal lord, Maqsud grew a romanticized view of the structure and simplicity of the Mainland's class system and concept of ownership. However, being from an isolated island with no personal experience and understanding of the cultural density and nuances of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archaina</a> and raised on an island where there is not much diversity in ethnicity and culture, he does not even fully grasp that the many cultures, languages, and customs of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archaina</a> are actually separate from each-other. His interpretation is aptly warped and distorted by his own projections of ambition, greed, and control. Due to this, he bastardizes the Archanian structures, names, and ideas with the conception of his own nation, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Numentellus</a>.<br>How can I present to the player without feeling too forced?
Mainland npcs complaining about how the new compulsory religion is messed up?
<br><br>Maqsud was born in the small mountain-side town of Maungatua on Aopuru under the name, Tāne. He has always had a general curiosity for chemistry, machinery, and discovering how the world works. At the age of 13, he stole copper scraps and sulfuric acid from a farmer in his town to experiment with. A typical punishment for stealing would be to cut the median nerve of the thief's right hand. This causes semipermanent paralyzation of hand function although the nerve function could still be recovered over time with rehabilitation. The farmer, having a young son himself, chose to show mercy by disrupting his left hand so that he could still be useful to society using his right. Tāne was left-handed.<br>
He is pretty butt-hurt about losing his dominant hand and begins searching for ways that he can restore its functionality quicker. He is quite clever and, while experimenting with his early form of batteries, notices how sending short electrical charges into his <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md#Shuchu Scar" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html#Shuchu_Scar" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu Scar</a> will sometimes excite his nerve tissue and make his body move. He continued researching this phenomenon, as well as ways to possibly use this in the reverse direction. At the age of 17, he develops the first early <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu Technology</a> controlled using his Median Interface.<br>
When he first meets Aition in the year 981, he is inspired by the stories from the mainland: their steel swords, armour, nations, and Kings. He begins developing the early prototypes for the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Toa.md" href="wiki/proficiency/toa.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Edge</a> and uses them to control a small number of towns in the area. It's here where he founds <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> and begins the process of the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Conversion.md" href="wiki/misc/the-great-conversion.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Great Conversion</a>.<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>Todo
write blurb on how Maqsud believes in the significance of names ... smth like

"Words mean nothing, but Names mean everything."

]]></description><link>wiki/characters/maqsud.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Characters/Maqsud.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 17:12:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Nīkau" href="wiki/characters/nīkau.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Nīkau</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
...
<br>Infobox

-<br>
-





<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>Dataview: No results to show for list query.<br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/characters/nīkau.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Characters/Nīkau.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:59:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Persephone" href="wiki/characters/persephone.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Persephone</a> (Nestis)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
The sinning Acolyte.
<br>Infobox

-<br>
-






<br>Found in <a class="internal-link" data-href="Desolation Valley.md" href="wiki/locations/desolation-valley.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Desolation Valley</a>

<br><br><br><br>Todo
She was not always named Persephone. She grew up in a nearby town close to 
<br><br><br>Transition from symbolism of harvest to that of death in second phase.<br><br>
<br>Angelic in silhouette.
<br>Sewn mouth (starvation).
<br><br>
<br>Predator: Sharp teeth emerge.
<br>Composed of bone/decaying appendages.
<br>But very skinny (bony) due to her sentence of eternal Nestis (starvation).
<br><br>Todo<br><br><br>Dataview: No results to show for list query.<br><br><br>Idea
A "god" as seen by the Numentellians ... originally that of the harvest ... but then Given the title of Persephone by Maqsud after breaking the pomegranate rule, reprimanded to watch over <a class="internal-link" data-href="Desolation Valley.md" href="wiki/locations/desolation-valley.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Desolation Valley</a>.
<br>Idea
A martyr representing the shortcomings of humans but also the free will and entropy of their souls ... they will make mistakes and pay the consequence ... meant as a figure of liberty but also as a cautionary tale about staying in line.
<br>How can Persephone fit into the thematic elements of the Shuchu

<br>Harvest, Springtime
<br>Death, Underworld
<br>Nestis: fasting, negative space

<br>death -&gt; conception


<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Persephone" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Persephone</a>

<br>free will, despite what is right... sin

<br>Eating the "Forbidden Fruit" == Flesh
<br>Sent to underworld as "punishment"
<br>connection between heaven and hell ... humanity, divine and sin

]]></description><link>wiki/characters/persephone.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Characters/Persephone.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:08:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="The Wisdom Bandit" href="wiki/characters/the-wisdom-bandit.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Wisdom Bandit</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Incomplete placeholder page<br><br>
He collects teeth ... will beat them out of you.
<br>Infobox

-<br>
Collects teeth ... will beat them out of you






<br>

<br><br><br><br>Teeth.<br><br>Question
Why does he collect teeth?<br>
Where is he from?
<br><br><br>
<br>Stocky body coated in scales of teeth... bound to his body via the fungus

<br>He will scrape a small hole from his skin and plug it with fungus and a molar.
<br>He will use different typed of teeth (molar, canine, incisor) to create patterns on his body, like tattoos.
<br>He wants to fully cover his body in teeth. 
<br>Also acts as armour.


<br>Will do ANYTHING for teeth ... even beat them out of you if he thinks he can.
<br>Think TLC documentary of person obsessed with BLANK.

<br>All other parts of life exists to support this one obsession.


<br>Is a <a class="internal-link" data-href="Chirurgeon.md" href="wiki/proficiency/chirurgeon.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Chirurgeon</a>, a surgeon specializing in fungal body implants and modifications.
<br>Wears glasses with the magnifier thing on them.
<br>Does he have good teeth himself?
<br>
<br><br><br><br><br>Dataview: No results to show for list query.<br><br><br>
<br>Wears glasses with the magnifier thing on them
<br>chimeras the teeth to his skin binding with shuchu
<br>if befriended, can provide <a class="internal-link" data-href="Chirurgeon.md" href="wiki/proficiency/chirurgeon.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Chirurgeon</a> services in exchange for teeth.
<br>mission... gather teeth from bosses... bounty style

<br>after, must fight ... 
<br>success: can provide Chirurgeon services for additional teeth collected


<br>has a reputation of performing surgery... but his patients are missing teeth when they awake.
<br>
What are those white scales covering his body?
]]></description><link>wiki/characters/the-wisdom-bandit.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Characters/The Wisdom Bandit.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:09:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archaina</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>(and its people)<br>
A continent much like Eurasia, containing many nations, cultures, and languages.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://azgaar.github.io/Fantasy-Map-Generator/" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://azgaar.github.io/Fantasy-Map-Generator/" target="_blank">map-gen</a><br>
<img src="lib/media/archaina.png"><br><br><br><br><br><br>Note

<br>Feudal, serfdom, villein
<br>Aition defects on a boat [980]
<br>great war ... steel armour and western tech spread through the continent. eastern gun powder also becomes a factor as arms race progress.
<br>Aition returns after 10 years [990]
<br>Shuchu planted on Mainland [999]
<br>Invasion years later [1005]

<br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/locations/archaina.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Locations/Archaina.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:45:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/archaina.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/archaina.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Desolation Valley" href="wiki/locations/desolation-valley.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Desolation Valley</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
Not desolate in life, but desolate in the soul. Home of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Persephone.md" href="wiki/characters/persephone.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Persephone</a>.
<br><br><br>A place where Numentellians dump all of their collected human and animal refuse to be digested by the Shuchu mycelium.<br><br><br>Named as a place desolate of the soul. All that exists there are the corpses and carcasses that belong to the Shuchu.<br><br><br>possible aesthetic 
<img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240716004654.png"><br>
by penusbmic
]]></description><link>wiki/locations/desolation-valley.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Locations/Desolation Valley.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:46:19 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20240716004654.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240716004654.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Numentellus</a> (Aopuru)]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>(and its people)<br><br><br>Home of the Numentellian peoples. It is located to the East of the the mainland, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="obsidian://open?vault=sometimeworld-vault&amp;file=Archaina" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="obsidian://open?vault=sometimeworld-vault&amp;file=Archaina" target="_blank">Archaina</a>. <br><br><br>The name is derived from the Latin word numen (divine) and tellus (land, region). It was given to the island by <a class="internal-link" data-href="Maqsud.md" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud</a> after the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Conversion.md" href="wiki/misc/the-great-conversion.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Great Conversion</a> and has a latin namesake due to his obsession with overseas culture.<br>
Before being named Numentellus, it was referred to as Aopuru, Maori for ao (cloud, land) and puru (blue), named after the soft blue soil of the island.<br><br><br>Numentellian are vegetarians. They benefit from the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md#Ecosystem" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html#Ecosystem" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu fertilization</a> property to get large crop yields. In return, they hunt for animals and leave their carcass to be absorbed by the fungus. In the local religion, it is treated at a sacrifice to their godly entity in return for crop fertility. <br><br><br>Historically, Numentellian have lived in smaller groups of people throughout the island relative peace aside from rare bouts over land and resources. Generally, thanks to the fungus, everyone was well fed and lived a life of excess. This was changed recently when a religious warlord, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Maqsud.md" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud</a>, founded The Church of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> and unified the island using <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu Technology</a>. They did not stop there, colonizing lands overseas and eventually reaching the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="obsidian://open?vault=sometimeworld-vault&amp;file=Archaina" rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="obsidian://open?vault=sometimeworld-vault&amp;file=Archaina" target="_blank">Archaina</a>.<br><br><br>Apart from Shuchu technology, the Numentellian are otherwise quite primitive. Crutched by the support of the fungus, Numentellians never had the motivation or need to innovate along the traditional pathway as the rest of the world: traditional agriculture, steel, gunpowder. Instead, they have innovated within the path of the Shuchu, developing somewhat analogous and extensions to traditional technology. Most of their technology after the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Conversion.md" href="wiki/misc/the-great-conversion.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Great Conversion</a> is composed of wood, copper alloys, and fungal tissue. See <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md#Fungal Utility" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html#Fungal_Utility" target="_self" rel="noopener">Fungal Utility</a><br>It is thought that Numentellus diverged from the outer world and developed its own technological pathway just before the widespread use of steel tools and irrigation; They are still in the Bronze Age and primarily employ hunter-gatherer means of sourcing food due to <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md#Ecosystem" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html#Ecosystem" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu fertilization</a> and the abundance of food.<br><br><br>As described in <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md#Fungal Utility" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html#Fungal_Utility" target="_self" rel="noopener">Fungal Utility</a>, The <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> have found many uses for the fungus. However, for thousands of years the extent of its uses were limited to <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md#Humans" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html#Humans" target="_self" rel="noopener">Agrarian</a><br><br><br>Is Numentellus the Garden of Eden??<br>some live underground  ... vertical living! more space]]></description><link>wiki/locations/numentellus.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Locations/Numentellus.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:03:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Storguard" href="wiki/locations/storguard.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Storguard</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
A Nordic culture and nation located in the northern area of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archaina</a>]
<br><br><br>
<br>Took over the french area from the franks in war explaining some of their french-names cities and Provence's like <a class="internal-link" data-href="Montmark.md" href="wiki/locations/montmark.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Montmark</a>.
<br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/locations/storguard.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Locations/Storguard.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:47:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Utmark" href="wiki/locations/utmark.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Utmark</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
Vast uninhabited land within the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Storguard.md" href="wiki/locations/storguard.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Storguard</a> realm.
<br><br><br><br><br>
<br>named by the {nords}: "uninhabited/empty lands"
]]></description><link>wiki/locations/utmark.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Locations/Utmark.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:59:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Church of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Founded by Maqsud as a centralization of Numentellian culture, society, and nationalism.
<br><br><br>Named by Maqsud as a combination of the Greek prefix Neo- (new) and the Latin word venia (forgiveness, indulgence) meant to stand for the <a class="internal-link" data-href="#The New Sin" href="about:blank#The_New_Sin" target="_self" rel="noopener">The New Sin</a> of Numentellians that they must absolve.<br><br><br>
A self-centred bastardization and blender of religions and myths around the world.
<br>Maqsud is seen as the absolute divine authority of the religion and nation. He controls the Shuchu, the fifth binding element surrounding the <a class="internal-link" data-href="#Four Acolytes" href="about:blank#Four_Acolytes" target="_self" rel="noopener">Four Acolytes</a>. He represents the primordial ambition of all human's strife for power and conquest.<br><br>Idea
Sin to eat the flesh of an animal, as that is to be preserved for the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu</a>.
<br><br>Ideas

<br>The binding of the four elements (earth, wind, water, fire)
<br>Numentellus (Aopuru) is the garden of Eden 
<br>Your body belongs to the Shuchu and must be returned ... Your soul belongs to yourself
<br>Persephone (Eve figure? pomegranate -&gt; apple??? original sin???)

<br>A martyr representing the shortcomings of humans but also the free will and entropy of their souls ... they will make mistakes and pay the consequence ... meant as a figure of liberty but also as a cautionary tale about staying in line.
<br>pomegranate (Meat) is a banned food (fruit of the Shuchu/dead)
<br>How does this segue into conquest of Mainland?
<br>atone for sin by sentence to eternal Nestis (fasting).


<br>Shuchu represents the underworld as it is where your body returns to after your soul (electricity) fades.

<br><br>Idea
It is said that the Messiah will arise and slay Maqsud, bringing peace to his tyranny and violent ways. This prophecy is said to have been fulfilled by {...}. But it turns out {...} is just Maqsud in disguise and the entire "prophecy" was just conceived to cleanse the church of the atrocities Maqsud committed on Archaina to establish the church. The player learns of this and decides to take this Messiah title upon their-self.
<br><br><br>Maqsud assigned the four Acolytes, adhering to the classical elements, their themes, and their purpose to the Neovenian Church. Each of these Acolytes hold meaning to Numentellian culture but also serve as a tragic cautionary tale to the followers.<br><br>
Water/Fluidity/Entropy AND Sin
<br>Persephone, the acolyte corresponding to Water of the four elements. Her symbolism extends to themes of Entropy, Harvest, and Sin. As Acolyte of the harvest, she represents the Shuchu's symbiotic plant stimulation but, despite that, commits the great sin by defying Maqsud and consuming the flesh of another animal. Maqsud displays his solidarity to the Acolytes by issuing a dispensation rather than killing Persephone, but shows his authority by sentencing her to eternal fasting in the {underworld}. Thus, she is awarded the alternate title, Nestis. See more: <a class="internal-link" data-href="Persephone.md" href="wiki/characters/persephone.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Persephone</a><br><br>
Flame/Light/Charge
<br>Boss notes

<br>Themes

<br>Consumption: fuel
<br>Light
<br>Charge


<br>Rebirth: if enough is consumed before killing, it will be reborn.

<br>mby have weak no-damage adds that both player and boss will kill. (referred to from boss as "fuel")
<br>when boss kills adds, adds to consumption. if enough killed, will respawn after defeated, indefinitely.
<br>balance by making boss independently easy though. but also last long enough to display the mechanic to the player.



<br><br>
Air/Void/Speed
<br>Boss notes
electricity, magnet
<br><br>
Earth/Structure/Body/Nature
<br>Boss notes
chimerism
<br><br><br>
<br>{Neo-} latin

<br>Neothriskeía : Greek
<br>Neodharma : Bengali
<br>Neolibertas : Latin, freedom
<br>Neovenia : Latin, pardon/indulgence


]]></description><link>wiki/misc/neovenia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Misc/Neovenia.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:59:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
"There is no hope in fighting anymore... It's already under our feet, on our food, in our bodies..."
<br><br><br>Shuchu is a fungus endemic to <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Numentellus</a> and is worshiped and utilized by the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Islander</a> peoples. The Shuchu technology has endless applications and mysteries that still have not been discovered by Humans.<br><br><br>The Shuchu works together with its environment to grow its own size and influence. It spreads under the earth over vast distances creating a mycelium that absorbs animal carcasses for nutrients and nerve tissue. Unlike many other fungi genera, rather than consuming an area, the Shuchu integrates its-self with an ecosystem to maximize and develop a renewable food source than just simply consuming. Shuchu will stimulate the growth of fruit bearing plants that grow over its mycelium using electrical current and supplementing it with nutrients found elsewhere in its network. Thus, with more available fruit and edible plants, more animal life is supported and more animal carcasses that can be absorbed by the network. It essentially farms animals.<br><br>One thing to note is that Shuchu will not absorb the cells of a living animal, it understands that a living animal can multiply if given the chance to live out its life, resulting in more food for the fungus in the long term. In areas that have a Shuchu mycelium, there is typically an abnormally large animal population.<br><br>The <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Islanders</a> are aware of the mechanics of the Shuchu. They benefit from the fertilization properties of the mycelium to grow food and they respect the Shuchu by refraining form eating the meat of an animal. Furthermore, some groups of humans will hunt animals and leave their carcasses in the forest as a sacrifice to the Shuchu as they know that animal matter is what the fungus feeds on.<br><br><br>Shuchu, the name given to the fungus by the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Islanders</a>, comes from the Japanese word 主柱 (central pillar of society) but is also curiously a homonym with the word 手中 (in ones own control). <br><br><br>Humans have discovered a ways to influence the fungus to perform mechanical and electrical functions. Takes advantage of their conductive and material properties.<br>
Uses include, weapons, logistics, communication, and body modification. See: <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu Technology</a><br><br>When a human is wounded, and their wound is exposed to the fungus, it will begin to disinfect and fill the wound with a hard blue tissue. Many <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Numentellian</a> have these Shuchu scar around their body akin to regular scars. These patches are the foundation to Shuchu technology as they provide the electrical-nervous interface that Shuchu tech is founded on.<br><br><br>Shuchu exists mostly in its mycelium "roots" but visually manifests naturally as a fruiting body. Its stem and cap have a faint blue colour and glow, most visible in low light. Its spores also have a faint glow and appear like floating blue fireflies around the fruiting bodies.<br>Idea
{smth about the mycelium glowing under certain circumstances}

<br>blue glowing ... bioluminiecence.
<br>coral-like fruits. of different types

<br>Sharp/Hard
<br>Spongey


<br>mainly in vein-like patterns below the surface.

<br>when removed from the ground, a ropey stringiness
<br>white with slight blue glow.



<br><br><img alt="Pasted image 20240712134200.png" src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240712134200.png" style="width: 300px; max-width: 100%;"><br>Possible Palettes

<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://lospec.com/palette-list/cryptic-ocean" target="_blank">https://lospec.com/palette-list/cryptic-ocean</a>
<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://lospec.com/palette-list/berry-nebula" target="_blank">https://lospec.com/palette-list/berry-nebula</a>
<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://lospec.com/palette-list/bluem0ld" target="_blank">https://lospec.com/palette-list/bluem0ld</a>
<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://lospec.com/palette-list/spectral-scarab" target="_blank">https://lospec.com/palette-list/spectral-scarab</a> (cyber-ish)
<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://lospec.com/palette-list/fantshat8" target="_blank">https://lospec.com/palette-list/fantshat8</a> (planty)

<br><br><br>
The fungus is relentless and horizontally organized... you can chop and burn all you are able, but there is always more... and there's no root, no head to cut off, no king to slay. 
<br>
There is no hope in fighting anymore... It's already under our feet, on our food, in our bodies...
<br><br><br>how is it fueled?

<br>neuron matter? dead animals are best. especially humans and their brain matter.
<br>symbiotic (Remoras)

<br>what happens if you eat one?

<br>

<br>small group names for fungus, such as isolated in machines or an interface... what called?

<br>Platoon
<br>Cluster
<br>Constellation
<br>Fleet

<br>Four classical elements: brought together?<br>
<br>Air: electricity
<br>Water: agriculture
<br>Earth: mycilium
<br>Fire: glowing blue<br>
Shuchu brings these elements together ... it is truth
]]></description><link>wiki/misc/shuchu.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Misc/Shuchu.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 14:31:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/pasted-image-20240712134200.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/pasted-image-20240712134200.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu Technology</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>During the consolidation era, the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> discovered a ways to influence the fungus to perform mechanical and electrical functions. Takes advantage of their conductive and material properties. Many of these devices have copper chassis and hardened fungus as the connective tissue. <br><br><br>Can interface with humans by being exposed to living nerve tissue. Most users choose to bind with the fungus through their hands and arms to get extended functionality from their tools. Simple devices with a small number of controlled variables can be operated through a Median interface, connected at the hand or along the arm. More complex devices mush be connected directly through the brain, using a neural interface. See <a class="internal-link" data-href="Maqsud.md#Background" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html#Background" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud's Background</a> for the beginning origins Shuchu interfacing.<br><br>Connects the users nervous system to any tools or machines that require limited control or input. Devices connected to the median interface often only require 1-3  continuous channels of input, much like how nerves send signals to contract muscles in a "vanilla" body. 📋<br><br>The extreme users bind with the fungus directly through their brain. They do this by undergoing a procedure consisting of removing a portion of their skull and introducing a fungal stem into the cavity. Overtime, the fungus will integrate with the users conscious. Eventually, the fungus is influenced to form a hardened shell and fill the skull cavity while still maintaining a neural interface. The user can then consciously connect and communicate with devices and others by connecting their neural interface with another.<br>Todo
risks of neural interface<br>
<a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trepanning" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trepanning</a>
<br><br><br><br>Across long distances where a fungal bed exists.<br><br>Due to the conductive and semi-conductive properties of the Shuchu, complex circuitry and neural structures are able to be formed within its network. This allows it to store and compute information similar to that of both computers and humans. This however, is not the Shuchu's natural state. Wherever it occurs, it is likely a structure induced by a human. See: <a class="internal-link" data-href="{computers}.md" href="wiki/proficiency/{computers}.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">{computers}</a><br><br>Originally made using brass frame and fungal mechanics, uses electro-magnetic fields to project matter in some direction. Effectively acting as guns. These are generally subsonic, but paired with high damaging projectiles is still more than fatal. <br>See:<br>
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Shotgunners.md" href="wiki/enemies/shotgunners.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shotgunners</a>: musket rail style frag loading
<br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Sluggunners.md" href="wiki/enemies/sluggunners.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Sluggunners</a>: casing rail style projectile
<br><br>Fungus can send an inductive charge through conductive material to heat it. These blades store a <a class="internal-link" data-href="Toa.md#Crescium" href="wiki/proficiency/toa.html#Crescium" target="_self" rel="noopener">special alloy</a> that greatly expands when heated but still maintaining rigid form, allowing for a blue-white-hot extendible blade much like a "light saber" from the Star Wars franchise. These Edges require a Median Interface to control the blade extension and heat. Some users have developed unique extensions to their Edges by making use of the fungus' properties. See: <a class="internal-link" data-href="Toa.md" href="wiki/proficiency/toa.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Toa</a><br><br>Because the fungus can interface with an animal's nervous system, it is also able to bridge nerve and biological pathways between tissue of genetically different humans and animals. This opens up an incredibly wide range of possibilities like brain-to-brain communication, enhancement and exchange of body parts, and medical limb and organ replacement. See: <a class="internal-link" data-href="Chimera.md" href="wiki/proficiency/chimera.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Chimera</a>]]></description><link>wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Misc/Shuchu Technology.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 17:57:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Stub Ideas" href="wiki/misc/stub-ideas.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Stub Ideas</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Stub Ideas not yet deserving of a page.
<br>]]></description><link>wiki/misc/stub-ideas.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Misc/Stub Ideas.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:59:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="The Great Conversion" href="wiki/misc/the-great-conversion.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Great Conversion</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br><br><br>
<br>"manifest destiny??"
<br>culminates in christening ALL THE LAND with the Shuchu
<br>lead by <a class="internal-link" data-href="Maqsud.md" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud</a>
]]></description><link>wiki/misc/the-great-conversion.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Misc/The Great Conversion.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:48:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Chimera.md" href="wiki/proficiency/chimera.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Chimera</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Any organism that is a fusion or composition of one or more animals or organisms. This is made possible by the neuron interface function of the Shuchu.
<br><br><br>Using the Shuchu's neural interfacing property, it can be used to fuse together body parts and limbs from one organism to another. This often takes the form of replacing limbs with those of the same species (ie. human to human) but also extends to implanting specialized organs to serve a purpose. In rarer cases, some ambitious humans are known to experiment with body parts of animals that drastically vary from their own genetic makeup. Because of the Shuchu's symbiotic nature, it is able to keep the both parties alive and healthy by osmotically transferring nutrients across its barrier.<br><br>The challenges of going "off gene" are that there is a higher likelihood of the auxiliary organ to be incompatible with the nutrients naturally produced by the host. This can lower the effectiveness of the organ and also cause its cells to die, leading to further complications such as infection and decay. Because of this, hosts with highly variable organs, often must  supplement their organs to supply the necessary nutrients or have new organs implanted to produce those nutrients autonomously. <br><br><br>Uses widely vary from replacement/enhancement/supplement of existing organs or body parts to completely new structures added to the body.<br><br>Todo

<br>primitive battery

<br>Copper-sulfate: Sulfuric acid
<br>Anode: Zinc
<br>Cathode: Copper


<br>electric eel implant.

<br><br>Homunculi are organism is heavily chimeric to an unrecognizable degree. <br><br>
<br>The more advanced chimera follow similar trends as the space marines from 40K.

<br>custom organs


]]></description><link>wiki/proficiency/chimera.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Proficiency/Chimera.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:10:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="Chirurgeon" href="wiki/proficiency/chirurgeon.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Chirurgeon</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
A surgeon that is specialized in <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu Technology</a> and medicine.
<br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/proficiency/chirurgeon.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Proficiency/Chirurgeon.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:47:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Toa.md" href="wiki/proficiency/toa.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Toa</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Those who wield Edges, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md#Median Interface" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html#Median_Interface" target="_self" rel="noopener">Median</a> gadgets that serve a similar purpose to a sword but rather than slicing with a blade, it burns through its target with white-hot metal. Like a "light-saber" from the Star Wars franchise, they can extend and retract into their handle. 
<br><br><br>Controlled by a <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu Technology.md#Median Interface" href="wiki/misc/shuchu-technology.html#Median_Interface" target="_self" rel="noopener">Median Interface</a>, the user must learn to control the amount of current continuously being supplied to the copper coil. Under-heating the {metal} will yield a cold and short blade. Over-heating the {metal} will lead to a soft blade prone to deformation or in-extreme cases, melting. <br>Edges are used very similarly to a traditional sword, but rather than cutting, the edge will burn right through the target. Most edges are hot enough to effortlessly pass through most flesh and materials. However, it has a more difficult time with steel, often bouncing off with a strike but softening it with heat in the process.<br>When used for prolonged periods, the blade and internals of the handle will get too hot to wield. Some users mitigate this by lowering the heat of their coils (conversely effecting their cutting ability) or other creative solutions. However, all users deal with the problem of overheating at some point or another.<br><br>This takes takes new users around 1-4 months of prehabilitation depending on the maturity of their median interface. It takes new users a large amount of concentration while in combat to simultaneously maintain a steady level of current to their coil. Consistency and quality of current is referred to by wielders as edge quality. It takes new users up to 4 seconds to extend and retract their blade.<br>Quote
"The blade quality was so poor, his edge functioned more like a searing club then a blade"
<br><br>More experienced users do not have to concentrate on their edge quality and can also extend and retract their blade much faster than beginners.<br><br>Seasoned Toa with a coordinated median interface, can extend their blades near instantaneously and even expand and retract during combat to give them more offensive options. They also are able to adjust their "edge quality" depending on the situation. This can depend on weather, armour of opponent, or to elongate the usage time before their handle overheats.<br><br><br>The handle of the Edge device is typically made of a brass chassis with a <a class="internal-link" data-href="Shuchu.md" href="wiki/misc/shuchu.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shuchu</a> interface near the hilt. Inside the chassis, there is a copper induction coil around a narrow cylinder of {metal}. The inside of the chassis is insulated with a silicone/rubber material to keep the handle from heating too much. <br><br>When the copper coil is provided with a current, the {metal} will expand in the direction of its cylindrical base and out the open end of the handle. The metal will expand proportionally to the heat it is given from the copper coil and begin to glow blue.<br><br>In addition to controlling their handle's current, wielders must supply large amount of power to their Edge. This must come from some battery or capacitive cell. Early in the development stage of these weapons, crude batteries, designed<br><br>Named from the Greek word cresco (grow,rise) and Latin suffix ium (metal)<br>
<br>cylindrical alloy that expands way more on the long axis than any other.
<br>very narrow blade... conductive heat transfer on touch is same, but radiative heat is much lower as it is proportional to area of emission.
<br>expands in single direction due to its atomic structure.
<br>properties

<br><br><br>Toa has a Maori meaning of victor, expert and warrior.<br><br><br>Todo
Advanced users will often modify their blades or develop their own to suit their styles and preferences.

<br>form
<br>blade length
<br>multiple blades

<br><br><br>
<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://www.uwa.edu.au/study/-/media/faculties/science/docs/electric-eels.pdf" target="_blank">https://www.uwa.edu.au/study/-/media/faculties/science/docs/electric-eels.pdf</a>
]]></description><link>wiki/proficiency/toa.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Proficiency/Toa.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 16:12:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="New Order" href="wiki/stories/new-order.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">New Order</a> [<span class="dataview dataview-inline-query"><span>1002</span></span>]]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br><br><br>Once Maqsud is killed, the Numentellions and the Archians come to agreements<br>Four years following the invasion, Aition finds himself continuing to search for {mis-solution}<br>Aition <br>by the end of chapter 2, Aition realises that {mis-solution} is a farce and Chapter 3 starts.<br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/stories/new-order.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Stories/New Order.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:49:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Sometimeworld.md" href="wiki/stories/sometimeworld.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Sometimeworld</a> [<span class="dataview dataview-inline-query"><span>1005</span></span>]]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
New King, new politics, new weapons, new religion, and an old Aition, left behind by both the old world and the new.
<br><br><br>Upon returning to the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mainland</a>, it has changed a lot. {...gunpowder....}<br>
Aition and the boy are not accepted by society and live a socially isolated life in one of the major city's. He lives in a world that has left him behind.<br>Once the invasion starts, <a class="internal-link" data-href="{young child}.md" href="{young child}" target="_self" rel="noopener">{young child}</a> is executed for being of invader decent and Aition is banished into a nomadic life.<br><br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/stories/sometimeworld.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Stories/Sometimeworld.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:49:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="The One King.md" href="wiki/stories/the-one-king.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">The One King</a> [<span class="dataview dataview-inline-query"><span>981</span></span>]]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
Beginnings of The Great Conversion until the Invasion
<br><br><br><a class="internal-link" data-href="Maqsud.md" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud</a>, an ambitions Numentellian listened closely to Aition's stories of the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mainland</a>. Land its possibly the one thing that Numentellians done have of excess, being bound to their island. Over recent years, population has been difficult to manage. Not by food or critical resources, but by density of people. Bumping into others on the street, crowded stores and bedchambers. This Numentellian longed for the open fields and loved the idea of becoming one of these Kings that Aition had spoke of.<br>How does Maqsud discover tech?

<br>hes been tinkering his whole childhood
<br>

<br>
<br>he builds <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> with goal of being the ONE KING
<br>develops fungal technology
<br>militarism and nationalism
<br>Unites <a class="internal-link" data-href="Numentellus.md" href="wiki/locations/numentellus.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Numentellus</a> over the <a class="internal-link" data-href="The Great Conversion.md" href="wiki/misc/the-great-conversion.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Great Conversion</a>
<br>begins conquest beyond the island
<br><br><br><br><br>
<br><a rel="noopener" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religious_war#Soga%E2%80%93Mononobe_conflict" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Religious_war#Soga%E2%80%93Mononobe_conflict</a>
<br>name

<br>Shaurya
<br>Toshi
<br>Nirvaan - final form ... no life or death
<br>Maqsud - intention, aim


<br>Once Aition learns his Edge, he leaves his steel sword in the town. it was taken by Maqsud and stored as a relic and a testing sample as the only steel on the island. 
]]></description><link>wiki/stories/the-one-king.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Stories/The One King.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:59:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Time Was.md" href="wiki/stories/time-was.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Time Was</a> [<span class="dataview dataview-inline-query"><span>978</span></span>]]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>
The origin story of our Aition
<br><br><br>Enter: <a class="internal-link" data-href="Aition.md" href="wiki/characters/aition.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aition</a><br>Aition Grew up in a small fishing town on the east coast of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Mainland</a>. Becoming tired of his life and having doubts about his future there, he joins a crew who is setting sale for new lands.<br>He eventually lands on a remote island with people. Their culture seems to be more primitive than back home: bronze age, tribal, hunter-gather. He settles for a time in a small <a class="internal-link" data-href="{mountain village}" href="{mountain village}" target="_self" rel="noopener">{mountain village}</a> and learns their language and ways. He shows the locals his steel tools, his sword, and tells them of his homeland. Wars, riches, nations, and Land: more land that could be possibly controlled by one King. <br>One particular local, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Maqsud.md" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud</a>, takes exceptional attention to these stories.<br>
"What if I could rule all that land?"<br>
-&gt; Branch into: <a class="internal-link" data-href="The One King.md" href="wiki/stories/the-one-king.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">The One King</a><br>The <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> seizes <a class="internal-link" data-href="{mountain village}" href="{mountain village}" target="_self" rel="noopener">{mountain village}</a> and only one person resists, perishing at the hands of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Maqsud.md" href="wiki/characters/maqsud.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Maqsud</a>'s own Edge, and leaving a young child as orphan. ~~Aition knows this child as <a class="internal-link" data-href="{young child}.md" href="{young child}" target="_self" rel="noopener">young child</a>, and takes him under his wing as they make off for a new home, away from the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a>. ~~<br>~~They wander island for several years. Over this time, the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> begins to gain influence, making more Shuchu technology available. Most significantly, for Aition, <a class="internal-link" data-href="Toa.md" href="wiki/proficiency/toa.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Edges</a>. Because the Edges burned white-hot, his steel sword became deprecated and no longer served him in protecting himself and <a class="internal-link" data-href="{young child}.md" href="{young child}" target="_self" rel="noopener">{young child}</a>. Since he was familiar with his steel sword, his transition to an Edge was more seamless than most, who were used to bronze spears and bows. ~~<br>~~The <a class="internal-link" data-href="Neovenia.md" href="wiki/misc/neovenia.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Neovenia</a> begins rapidly seizing power using their new fungal technology and religion to unite the island under one name {...}. Due to nationalistic and cultural instability on the island, Aition decides to return home and document his travels and discoveries back in the <a class="internal-link" data-href="Archaina.md" href="wiki/locations/archaina.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mainland</a>. He brings the boy because, just like his younger self, he doubts his future in Numentellus. ~~<br><br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/stories/time-was.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Stories/Time Was.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:51:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a data-href="The Ursōrum" href="wiki/characters/the-ursōrum.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">The Ursōrum</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
He who possesses bear.
<br>Infobox

-<br>
He who possesses bear.





<br><br><br>Name: <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Appendix:Glossary#genitive_case" rel="noopener" class="external-link" title="Appendix:Glossary" href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Appendix:Glossary#genitive_case" target="_blank">genitive</a> <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Appendix:Glossary#plural_number" rel="noopener" class="external-link" title="Appendix:Glossary" href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/Appendix:Glossary#plural_number" target="_blank">plural</a> of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/ursus#Latin" rel="noopener" class="external-link" title="ursus" href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/ursus#Latin" target="_blank">ursus</a>.<br>Is he a islander or mainlander? probably affiliated with the cult.<br><br><br><br><br><br><br>Dataview: No results to show for list query.<br><br>]]></description><link>wiki/characters/the-ursōrum.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Characters/The Ursōrum.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 20:46:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[<a class="internal-link" data-href="Montmark.md" href="wiki/locations/montmark.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Montmark</a>]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>placeholder page<br><br>
A small province on the North-East coast of <a class="internal-link" data-href="Storguard.md" href="wiki/locations/storguard.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">Storguard</a>
]]></description><link>wiki/locations/montmark.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">wiki/Locations/Montmark.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[sawyer tang]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 14:11:52 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>